Inventory of the Rebecca Flint papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Rebecca Flint papers
1913-1920
1918-1919
59014
Hoover Institution Archives
2 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes (1.6 linear feet)
Booklets, newspapers, other printed matter, and photographs relating to Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) work with the American Expeditionary Forces in France, and more generally the life of an American in France during World War I.
Flint, Rebecca.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1959.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the library catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Rebecca Punchard Flint was born in Madison, Wisconsin on June 13, 1892. She received her A.B. from Wellesley College in 1914 and later her A.M. from the University of Wisconsin in 1923. In between receiving her degrees, she worked with the YMCA as a relief worker in France from 1918-1919.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Rebecca Flint papers consist of booklets, newspapers, other printed matter, and photographs relating to Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) work with the American Expeditionary Forces in France and, more broadly, World War I and its effects in France. The content of this collection includes both personal items, such as travel documents and a diary, and items that relate to the war experience of Americans in France in general, such as booklets, newspapers, programs, and photographs. The bulk of the collection was collected from 1918 to 1919.
United States. Army. American Expeditionary Forces.; World War, 1914-1918--France.; World War, 1914-1918--War work.; Young Men's Christian associations.
- Rebecca Flint's Personal Documents, 1916-1920
  - YMCA paperwork, 1916-1920 (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Travel paperwork, 1919 (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1917-1919 (Box-folder 1:5)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes a map of the Near East, recipe book, checkbook, and service flags, among other material.
  - "My Little Diary,", 1919 (Box-folder 1:9)
- Photographs, 1913-1920
  - Photographs, 1913-1919 (Box-folder 2:5-8)
    Scope and Contents note
    Subjects include World War I soldiers, European scenery, and the destruction of war.
  - Panoramics, 1918-1920 (Box 3)
    Many of the panoramic photographs have descriptions and soldiers' names on the backs. The photographs taken in Paris highlight the ruins post World War I.
    - Officers 380th Infantry 95th Division
    - 1st Lieutenant 380th Infantry
    - The Town Hall (Paris)
    - The Square and the Church (Paris)
    - The Basilica (Paris)
    - 151st Depot Brigade Officers, 1918
    - Army appointment certificate, 1917
- Printed Matter, 1913-1919
  - Programs, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - University literature, 1917-1919 (Box-folder 1:4)
    Includes a convocation speech from the University of Wisconsin given in 1917 and course listings of available classes for Americans in France from the University of Grenoble and the University of Paris in 1919.
  - Booklets, 1918-1919
    - "New Testament,", 1919 (Box-folder 1:6)
    - "A Prayer Book for Soldiers and Sailors,", 1919 January 27 (Box-folder 1:6)
    - "The American Soldier's Souvenir of Aix-les-Bains,", 1919 May 2-3 (Box-folder 1:7)
    - "Chateau Thierry,", 1919 July 8 (Box-folder 1:7)
    - "106th Regt. Engrs. of Dixie Division: Builders of Camp Pontanezen,", 1919 (Box-folder 1:7)
    - "How We Won the War,", 1919 (Box-folder 1:7)
    - "War Information Series: America's War Aims and Peace Program,", 1918 November (Box-folder 1:7)
    - "U.S. Army Facts and Insignia,", 1918 (Box-folder 1:7)
    - "Army Song Book U.S.,", 1919 June (Box-folder 1:7)
    - "The Dauphine Leave Area: A Historical and Geographical Sketch,", 1919 (Box-folder 1:8)
    - "Souvenir Booklet of Brest,", 1919 May 26 (Box-folder 1:8)
    - "Inter-Allied Games Pershing Stadium Paris,", 1919 (Box-folder 1:9)
    - "Wisconsin Federation of Women's Clubs,", 1919 (Box-folder 1:9)
    - "France: Our Ally,", 1919 February 14 (Box-folder 1:9)
    - "The Religious Program of the Young Men's Christian Association with the American Expeditionary Forces in Europe,", 1918 (Box-folder 1:9)
  - Postcards, 1913-1919 (Box-folder 2:3-4)
    Include locations in the United States, France, Germany, and England.
  - Newspapers and clippings, 1919
    - Newspaper clippings, 1919 (Box-folder 2:1-2)
      Contain articles about the World War I 1919 Armistice and victory celebrations from multiple newspapers.
    - The Amaroc News, 1919 June 29 (Box-folder 4:1)
    - The New York Herald, 1919 July 15 (Box-folder 4:2)
    - The Alpine American, 1919 May 2 (Box-folder 4:3)
    - The Circulator Sixth Division, 1919 April 9 (Box-folder 4:4)
    - New York Times, 1919 August (Box-folder 4:5)
    - The Stars and Stripes, 1919 June 13 (Box-folder 4:6)
    - Stray Shot, 1919 April 11 (Box-folder 4:7)
    - Le Matin, 1919 July 14 (Box-folder 4:8)
    - Excelsior, 1919 March 15 (Box-folder 4:9)
    - The Alpine American, 1919 June 6 (Box-folder 4:10)
    - Le Pays de France, 1919 February 6 (Box-folder 4:11)
    - The Flash, 1919 April 10 (Box-folder 4:12)